Yes, this is a spreadsheet.
没错 这是一个电子表格
It has columns of data and row entries.
它包含了数据列和条目行
What you need to do with this ledger is something
对于该总账 你要做的是
like keep a running total of the columns.
计算各列的总计
Sum the columns for each page and then carry that forward to the next page.
对每页上的各列求和 然后转到下一页
Oh, forgot something, this makes it electronic.
忘了一件事 这个让一切电子化了
Right?
对吧？
Can you imagine how much time it took to keep those spreadsheets up to date?
你能想象让这些电子表格保持最新状态需要花费多少时间吗？
Tracking sales, inventory accounts or really, any kind of list.
跟踪销量、库存帐号或任何数据
I'm here at the Computer History Museum in Mountain View where we can
我现在位于山景城的计算机历史博物馆中
see firsthand the early platforms used for spreadsheets.
我们可以亲自查看早期用于电子表格的平台
In 1979 the first microcomputer spreadsheet VisiCalc came out for the Apple 2,
在 1979 年 出现了首个面向 Apple 2 的微电脑电子表格 VisiCalc
but it really gained popularity when it was ported to the IBM PC in 1981.
但是真正吸引大家关注的是于 1981 年在 IBM PC 平台上推出的应用
Suddenly, all office workers accounting, engineering, sales,
忽然之间 所有办公人员、会计、工程师、销售人员
management could use a PC to track and chart all kinds of data.
管理人员都可以使用电脑跟踪和绘制各种数据
This was the first killer app meaning that companies
它变成了第一个超级热门的应用
started buying IBM PCs just so they could have this application.
企业开始购买 IBM PC 机 只是为了使用这款应用
I remember when it happened.
我记得很清晰
Suddenly, we had an area in our office repurposed for several IBM PCs with not one,
忽然我们的办公室内引入了好几台 IBM PC 机
but two floppy drives.
它们有两个软盘驱动 而不是一个
That was A and B,
即 A 和 B
which the engineers and managers in my office used exclusively
我们办公室的工程师和管理者
for Lotus 1-2-3 spreadsheets and word processing apps.
专门用它们使用 Lotus 1-2-3 电子表格和文字处理应用
Before spreadsheets, it was a major chore to extract
在出现电子表格之前 提取有意义的信息
meaningful information and gain insight about the bigger picture in a company or process.
并对公司或某个流程有整体的了解是一项大工程
With a spreadsheet, the data could be moved around, corrected or inserted.
有了电子表格后 可以随意移动数据 更正或插入数据
We can add formulas of all kinds to columns or aggregate information from a list,
我们可以向列中添加各种公式 或汇总列表中的信息
maybe a sum or an average,
可以求和或求均值
we could compare information groups within our dataset.
可以对比数据集中不同群组的信息
There are limitations though.
但是存在限制条件
If you have a lot of users at the same time or
如果同时有很多用户
if the data set is very large your performance may suffer.
或者数据集非常庞大 那么性能可能会受到影响
The capacity of a spreadsheet application,
不同应用之间的功能
the maximum size of the sheets and how many there can be varies with the application.
工作表的大小上限以及数量上限各不相同
But spreadsheets are easy to obtain and use.
但是电子表格很容易获取和使用
The ability to quickly load,
通过电子表格能够快速加载、修改和对比数据
modify and compare to see your data and what it means is powerful.
使你能够了解数据并发现其中的含义
This is why you need a good understanding of what you can accomplish with spreadsheets.
因此我们需要深入了解电子表格具备的功能
With a little practice,
只需稍加练习
the process is fast and easy.
电子表格使用起来就很快速简单